<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>e-flux &#187; Announcements</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.e-flux.com/category/announcements/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.e-flux.com</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 05:00:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Laure Prouvost</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/laure-prouvost-4/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/laure-prouvost-4/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 05:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fahrenheit]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005420</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ Fahrenheit is delighted to present A Way to Leak, Lick, Leek, Laure Prouvost's first solo presentation in Los Angeles. Drawing from desire, oneirism, and a fantasized depiction of nature, Prouvost's immersive films and installations challenge the relationship between language and understanding through complex stories and surreal moments with her unusual approach to cinematic conventions and imagery.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead landscape">
<div class="image">
            <a href="http://fahrenheit.flaxfoundation.org/"><br />
	    <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/75d5c_8200_39e822f2ee52710b9309427e71f51350.jpg?b8c429" alt="Laure Prouvost at Fahrenheit" /><br />
            </a>				</p>
<p class="caption">Laure Prouvost, Lick in the Past (production still), 2016. Film. © Fahrenheit. </p>
</p>
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1>Laure Prouvost<br/><i>A Way To Leak, Lick, Leek</i></h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about">January 31–April 9, 2016</p>
<p> <b>Opening:</b> January 30, 7–10pm </p>
<p> <b>Fahrenheit</b> <br/>2245 E. Washington Blvd. <br/>Los Angeles, CA 90021<br/>United States </p>
<p> <a href="http://fahrenheit.flaxfoundation.org/">fahrenheit.flaxfoundation.org</a> <br/><a href="https://www.facebook.com/Fahrenheit-716266308406790/?fref=ts" class="link-social">Facebook</a></p>
</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Flaure-prouvost-4%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p>&#8220;When we move by night at the speed of desire<br/> With you at the wheel my limit goes higher<br/> Just turn me on, you turn me on<br/> You are my petrol, my drive, my dream, my exhaust&#8221;</p>
<p> <br/> Fahrenheit is delighted to present <i>A Way to Leak, Lick, Leek</i>, Laure Prouvost&#8217;s first solo presentation in Los Angeles. Drawing from desire, oneirism, and a fantasized depiction of nature, Prouvost&#8217;s immersive films and installations challenge the relationship between language and understanding through complex stories and surreal moments with her unusual approach to cinematic conventions and imagery. Prouvost&#8217;s attention to her environment, as well as the natural and human elements surrounding her, comprise the primary material of her work.</p>
<p> <i>A Way to Leak, Lick, Leek</i> is the outcome of Prouvost&#8217;s residency at Fahrenheit completed in the spring of 2015, and is the counterpart of the artist&#8217;s project presented last year at Musée départemental d&#8217;art contemporain de Rochechouart in France. The exhibition results in a site-specific installation of films, sculptures, and drawings utilizing elemental material found within Los Angeles—flora, fauna, smells, sounds, abandoned objects, and the vertiginous light of L.A.</p>
<p> Laure Prouvost constructs an immersive environment in which her works become central ploys in a scenario that explores the boundaries of fantastic and urban escapism. Her series of drawings and films reflect a delineated urban experience made of driving in L.A. and breathing in petrol and plastic smells. For her main installation, Prouvost coated the floor of the gallery space with blue resin, ornamenting its surface with shattered technological junk, abandoned tropical trees, floating pineapples, and branches of tumble weeds—an apocalyptic vision reminiscent of a private pool the morning after a wild night. In her new video, <i>A Lick to The Past</i>, filmed last spring in Downtown Los Angeles, she employs tropes both derived from and challenging the filmic languages of cinema and art. Adolescent Angelinos and their collective performance constitute an amateur form, on an improvisational level, acting on a parking lot to the sound of an original hip-hop track specially composed by L.A.-based producer WYNN for the exhibition. These stars of the outtake bring corrupt reveries to life through humor and mistranslations.</p>
<p> Curated by Martha Kirszenbaum</p>
<p> <b>Laure Prouvost</b> was born in 1961 in Uhnreka, USSR. She lives and works in a trailer moving from urban to rural environment, currently in the Croatian desert. Solo exhibitions include <i>We Would Be Floating Away from the Dirty Past</i> at the Haus Der Kunst, Munich (2016),<i> We Will Go Far </i>at Musée Départemental d&#8217;Art Contemporain de Rochechouart, Rochechouart (2015)<i>, It, Heat, Hit </i>at e-flux, New York (2015)<i>, Dear dirty dark drink drift down deep droll (in der dole) </i>at carlier | gebauer, Berlin (2015)<i>, Der Öffentlichkeit — Von Den Freunden Haus Der Kunst </i>at Haus der Kunst, Munich (2015),<i> For Forgetting</i> at New Museum, New York (2014), <i>From Wantee to Some Signs</i> at Extra City Kunsthal, Antwerp (2014); <i>Laure Prouvost / Adam Chodzko</i> at Tate Britain, London (2013); <i>All These Things Think Link</i> at Flat Time House, London (2010); <i>It, Heat, Hit</i> at Art Now Lightbox, Tate Britain, London (2010). Group shows include <i>The Great Acceleration</i> at the Taipei Biennial (2014); <i>Portraits d&#8217;Intérieurs</i> at the Nouveau Musée National de Monaco; and <i>Assembly: A Survey of Recent Artists&#8217; Film and Video in Britain 2008–2013</i> at Tate Britain, London (2013). Provoust received the Max Mara Art Prize for Women in 2011 and the Turner Prize in 2013.</p>
<p> <b>A</b><b>bou</b><b>t </b><b>Fahrenheit</b><br/> Fahrenheit is a non-profit initiative dedicated to research and creation in the field of contemporary art. Conceived by FLAX and developed by director and curator Martha Kirszenbaum, it is an interrelated residency program and a space dedicated to exhibitions, performances, film programs and talks. It supports the exchange and integration of France-related artists, curators and critics with a particular emphasis on outreach programs in communities within greater Los Angeles.</p>
<p> <b>A</b><b>bou</b><b>t </b><b>F</b><b>L</b><b>AX</b><br/> FLAX (France Los Angeles Exchange) is a non-profit 501(c)(3) charity based in Los Angeles. Founded in 2006, FLAX works to facilitate cultural exchange between Los Angeles and France through public and cultural events in Southern California. Recognizing and reinforcing the crucial links between these two cultural epicenters, FLAX works closely with local organizations, pooling private and corporate resources to foster cultural dialogue between French and American people in the United States. With its independent structure, FLAX operates with autonomy and transparency. Operating costs have been reduced to a minimum in order to turn the maximum of donations into efficient programs.<br/><a href="http://www.flaxfoundation.org/">www.flaxfoundation.org</a></p>
<p> <b>Media contact</b>: <a href="mailto:fahrenheit@flaxfoundation.org">fahrenheit@flaxfoundation.org</a></p>
<p>  </p>
<p> The exhibition was made possible by generous support from the <a href="http://www.institutfrancais.com/en">Institut Français</a>.</p>
</p>
<p><a href="http://www.institutfrancais.com/en" target="_blank"></a></p>
</p>
<div><a href="http://www.institutfrancais.com/en"><img src="http://editor.e-flux-systems.com/images/8200_5805b82b24ff1e63a40cd009d33bc114.jpg?w=150&#038;h=150&#038;c=0" alt="Laure Prouvost at Fahrenheit"/></a></div>
</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/laure-prouvost-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everywhen</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/everywhen/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/everywhen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 05:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harvard Art Museums]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005422</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Everywhen: The Eternal Present in Indigenous Art from Australia surveys contemporary Indigenous art from Australia, exploring the ways in which time is embedded within Indigenous artistic, social, historical, and philosophical life. For Indigenous people, the past is understood to be part of a cyclical and circular order known as the "everywhen;" conceptions of time rely on active encounters with both the ancestral and natural worlds.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead portrait">
<div class="image">
            <a href="http://www.harvardartmuseums.org/visit/exhibitions/4983/everywhen-the-eternal-present-in-indigenous-art-from-australia?utm_source=EFLUX&#038;utm_medium=EMAIL&#038;utm_campaign=EVERYWHEN"><br />
	    <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/4d110_8046_21a3565dc26a2b6b717864341ef8a486.jpg?b8c429" alt="Everywhen at the Harvard Art Museums" /><br />
            </a>				</p>
<p class="caption">Tommy Watson, <em>Wipu Rockhole</em>, 2004. Synthetic polymer paint on canvas. Art Gallery of New South Wales, Sydney, purchased with funds provided by the Aboriginal Collection Benefactors&#8217; Group 2004, 256.2004. © Tommy Watson. Courtesy of Yanda Aboriginal Art. </p>
</p>
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1><i>Everywhen: The Eternal Present in Indigenous Art from Australia</i></h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about">February 5–September 18, 2016</p>
<p> <b>Opening:</b> February 4, 5–10pm, with an after-hours preview and a panel discussion </p>
<p> <b>Harvard Art Museums</b> <br/>32 Quincy Street <br/>Cambridge, MA 02138<br/>USA <br/><b>Hours: </b> Monday–Sunday 10am–5pm </p>
<p> <a href="http://www.harvardartmuseums.org/visit/exhibitions/4983/everywhen-the-eternal-present-in-indigenous-art-from-australia?utm_source=EFLUX&amp;utm_medium=EMAIL&amp;utm_campaign=EVERYWHEN">www.harvardartmuseums.org</a> <br/><a href="https://www.twitter.com/harvartmuseums" class="link-social">Twitter</a> / <a href="https://www.facebook.com/harvardartmuseums?utm_source=EFLUX&amp;utm_medium=EMAIL&amp;utm_campaign=EVERYWHEN" class="link-social">Facebook</a> / <a href="http://instagram.com/harvardartmuseums?utm_source=EFLUX&amp;utm_medium=EMAIL&amp;utm_campaign=EVERYWHEN" class="link-social">Instagram</a></p>
</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Feverywhen%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p><i>Everywhen: The Eternal Present in Indigenous Art from Australia</i> surveys contemporary Indigenous art from Australia, exploring the ways in which time is embedded within Indigenous artistic, social, historical, and philosophical life. For Indigenous people, the past is understood to be part of a cyclical and circular order known as the &#8220;everywhen;&#8221; conceptions of time rely on active encounters with both the ancestral and natural worlds. While the exhibition focuses on the last 40 years of Indigenous art, it also includes historical objects from the rich collections of Harvard Univer­sity&#8217;s Peabody Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology to underscore both the continuity of cultural practice and remarkable adaptive innovations.</p>
<p> The <a href="http://www.harvardartmuseums.org/visit/exhibitions/4983/everywhen-the-eternal-present-in-indigenous-art-from-australia">exhibition</a> showcases more than 70 works drawn from public and private collections in Australia and the United States, and features many works that have never been seen outside Australia. Works by some of the most significant contemporary Indigenous artists will be on view, including Rover Thomas and Emily Kam Kngwarray (both former representatives at the Venice Biennale); Judy Watson, recipient of the 2006 Clemenger Contemporary Art Award; Doreen Reid Nakamarra, who participated in dOCUMENTA (13); Vernon Ah Kee, who has also exhibited at the Venice Biennale, and most recently, the Istanbul Biennial; and the visual and performance artist Christian Thompson, who was recently mentored by Marina Abramović in Australia.</p>
<p> An exhibition of this scope has not been seen in the United States for more than 25 years, and it reflects the ways in which the art historical landscape has shifted since then. Indigenous art is no longer positioned as &#8220;other,&#8221; but as another form of contemporary art that demands our critical attention. This exhibition presents an opportunity to introduce audiences to the central role that Indigenous art plays in the global narrative of contemporary art.</p>
<p> The analytical laboratory of the <a href="http://www.harvardartmuseums.org/teaching-and-research/research-centers/straus-center-for-conservation-and-technical-studies">Straus Center for Conservation and Technical Studies</a> at the Harvard Art Museums, a world leader in conserva­tion and conservation science, is also carrying out the first-ever large-scale techni­cal examination of traditional Indigenous bark paintings as part of the exhibition. Understanding the materials used by the artists will provide enormous insights into the long-standing practices and traditions of Indigenous painting.</p>
<p> The <a href="http://shop.harvardartmuseums.org/collections/frontpage/products/everywhen-the-eternal-present-in-indigenous-art-from-australia">exhibition catalogue</a>, published by the Harvard Art Museums and distributed by Yale University Press, includes images of the works on display and six essays by distinguished scholars. The publication delves more deeply into the concepts proposed in the exhibition, offering a lasting look at Indigenous Australian art, and paying homage to the particular traditions of specific regions of Australia.</p>
<p> Guest curated for the Harvard Art Museums by Indigenous Australian Stephen Gilchrist, of the Yamatji people of the Inggarda language group of Western Australia. Gilchrist is the Australian Studies Visiting Curator at the Harvard Art Museums and associate lecturer in art history at the University of Sydney, Australia.</p>
<p> Lead support for <i>Everywhen: The Eternal Present in Indigenous Art from Australia</i> and related research has been provided by the Harvard Committee on Australian Studies. The exhibition is supported by the Australian Government through the Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade and the Australian Consulate-General, New York. Additional support for the exhibition, catalogue, and related research has been provided by the Robert Lehman Foundation, John and Barbara Wilkerson, the American Friends of the National Gallery of Australia, Debra and Dennis Scholl, the William E. Teel African and Oceanic Arts Endowment, the Dimitri Hadzi Memorial Fund for Modern Art, and the Harvard Art Museums Mellon Publication Funds, including the Henry P. McIlhenny Fund. Modern and contemporary art programs at the Harvard Art Museums are made possible in part by generous support from the Emily Rauh Pulitzer and Joseph Pulitzer, Jr., Fund for Modern and Contemporary Art.</p>
</p>
<p><a href="http://www.harvardartmuseums.org/?utm_source=EFLUX&amp;utm_medium=EMAIL&amp;utm_campaign=EVERYWHEN%20" target="_blank"></a></p>
</p>
<div><a href="http://www.harvardartmuseums.org/?utm_source=EFLUX&#038;utm_medium=EMAIL&#038;utm_campaign=EVERYWHEN%20"><img src="http://editor.e-flux-systems.com/images/8046_a7e5b9aeefb98fc9bb4966fcf114d413.jpg?w=150&#038;h=150&#038;c=0" alt="Everywhen at the Harvard Art Museums"/></a></div>
</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/everywhen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Koki Tanaka</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/koki-tanaka-2/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/koki-tanaka-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 05:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Contemporary Art Gallery, Art Tower Mito]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005424</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This exhibition marks the first large solo exhibition of Koki Tanaka in Japan. The artist has drawn much attention in recent years for his activities—which seek an alternative perspective and attitude to current social situations and existing frameworks—conducted through a variety of means such as video documentation, installation, writing, performance and organizing events.
 In the 55th Venice Biennale in 2013, Tanaka presented video works that included one that showed five potters working together on one piece of pottery. Representing the beauty and difficulty of the act of collaborating on one thing, his works received international acclaim.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead landscape">
<div class="image">
            <a href="http://arttowermito.or.jp/index_en.html"><br />
	    <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/b80dd_9755_75c7c6eeca160d2a5b606878ce4a3a90.jpg?b8c429" alt="Koki Tanaka at Contemporary Art Gallery, Art Tower Mito" /><br />
            </a>				</p>
<p class="caption">&#8220;Provisional Studies: Workshop #4 Possibilities for being together. Their configuration,&#8221; (production still) 2015–16. 6-day communal retreat with workshops, video documentation. </p>
</p>
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1>Koki Tanaka<br/><i>Possibilities for being together. Their praxis.</i></h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about">February 20–May 15, 2016</p>
<p> <b>Contemporary Art Gallery, Art Tower Mito</b> <br/>1-6-8 Goken-cho <br/>Mito-shi <br/>Ibaraki 310-0063 <br/>Japan <br/><b>Hours: </b> Tuesday–Sunday 9:30am–6pm</p>
<p> T +81 29 227 8111 <br/><a href="MAILTO:cacpr@car.ocn.ne.jp">cacpr@car.ocn.ne.jp</a> </p>
<p> <a href="http://arttowermito.or.jp/index_en.html">arttowermito.or.jp</a> <br/><a class="link-social"/></p>
</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Fkoki-tanaka-2%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p>This exhibition marks the first large solo exhibition of Koki Tanaka in Japan. The artist has drawn much attention in recent years for his activities—which seek an alternative perspective and attitude to current social situations and existing frameworks—conducted through a variety of means such as video documentation, installation, writing, performance and organizing events.</p>
<p> In the 55th Venice Biennale in 2013, Tanaka presented video works that included one that showed five potters working together on one piece of pottery. Representing the beauty and difficulty of the act of collaborating on one thing, his works received international acclaim.</p>
<p> This exhibition focuses on Tanaka&#8217;s activity after 2010—when he started to be interested in collaboration—unveiling the new work juxtaposed with his recent works.</p>
<p> The new work produced for this exhibition is based on a six-day lodging and a series of workshops conducted during that time. General participants, facilitators and camera crews stayed together under one roof. Throughout the six days—which consisted of reading, cooking, making pottery, and workshops related to social movements, discussion, interviews and so forth—the opportunity was there for everyone to think, to have dialogues and to practice about &#8220;moving and community.&#8221;</p>
<p> In the exhibition, several video works based on the video documentation of the workshop are exhibited alongside items such as notes the artist made during the production.</p>
<p> <b>Notes on November 8, 2015 (the artist statement)</b><br/> On what kind of occasion do you open your heart to someone you have met for the first time?<br/> In what kind of situation do you help someone next to you?<br/> For what kind of reason do you trust someone, entrusting them with your own vulnerability?<br/> We were living together and participating in a workshop in the mountains, away from everyday life. The camera crew stayed there as well, documenting the whole scene. I was there, you were there, and none of us know what it means yet. We cooked, read, enunciated, moved around, conversed, thought about society, did pottery and discussed. In a small society, we confirm our own positions, re-question our roles and sometimes find ourselves at a loss. We encounter the other, and care about that other in this way. You try to be together with someone you barely know, or even with others you can barely understand. To some, this situation is a natural one, while to others, it is something difficult to accept. The situation in this 6-day workshop may be provisional, artificial and temporary. However, if it is possible even temporarily, is it not possible whenever, wherever and with whatever?<br/> –Koki Tanaka</p>
<p> <a href="http://kktnk.com/"><b>Koki Tanaka</b></a><br/> Born in 1975. Currently lives and works in Los Angeles. In his diverse art practice spanning video, photography, site-specific installations and interventional projects, Tanaka visualizes and reveals the multiple contexts latent in the most simple of everyday acts. In his recent projects, he has documented behaviors that were unconsciously exhibited by people confronting unusual situations—such as one piece of pottery being made by five potters and a piano being played by five pianists simultaneously—seeking to reveal group dynamics in a micro-society and temporal community.</p>
<p> Tanaka has shown widely, including exhibitions with the Hammer Museum (Los Angeles), the Yerba Buena Center for the Arts (San Francisco), the Mori Art Museum (Tokyo), the Taipei Biennial 2006 (Taipei), the Gwangju Biennial 2008 (Gwangju, Korea), the Yokohama Triennale 2011 (Yokohama, Japan), and the Japan pavilion at the 55th Venice Biennale. He received a Special Mention for National Participation at the 55th Venice Biennale and the Deutsche Bank Artist of the Year 2015 award.</p>
<p> Press contact: Minami Kanesawa, <a href="mailto:cacpr@car.ocn.ne.jp">cacpr@car.ocn.ne.jp</a></p>
<p> Organized by: Mito Arts Foundation<br/> Grants from: The Kao Foundation for Arts and Sciences, The Asahi Shimbun Foundation<br/> Sponsored by: Vitamin Creative Space<br/> Supported by: AOYAMA|MEGURO, Asahi Breweries, LTD., ARTISTS&#8217; GUILD, The Japan Foundation<br/> Curated by: Yuu Takehisa (Curator, Contemporary Art Center, Art Tower Mito)</p>
</p>
<p><a href="http://arttowermito.or.jp/index_en.html" target="_blank"></a></p>
</p>
<div><a href="http://arttowermito.or.jp/index_en.html"><img src="http://editor.e-flux-systems.com/images/9755_beb0d16cb6160d0f2aa75fa8d52e905e.jpg?w=150&#038;h=150&#038;c=0" alt="Koki Tanaka at Contemporary Art Gallery, Art Tower Mito"/></a></div>
</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/koki-tanaka-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Close-Up – A New Generation of Film and Video Artists in the Netherlands</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/close-up-a-new-generation-of-film-and-video-artists-in-the-netherlands/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/close-up-a-new-generation-of-film-and-video-artists-in-the-netherlands/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 05:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[EYE]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005426</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From January 31 to May 22, 2016, EYE presents the exhibition Close-Up—A New Generation of Film and Video Artists in the Netherlands. This group exhibition features numerous recent film and video works and spatial installations by a new generation of filmmakers and artists in the Netherlands, who are breaking down the barriers between film, video, and visual art.
 Participating artists/ filmmakers:
 Melanie Bonajo (1978), Felix Burger (1982), Helen Dowling (1982), Zachary Formwalt (1979), Hamza Halloubi (1982), Mariska de Groot (1982), Cristóbal León &#038; Joaquín Cociña (1980 &#038; 1980), Amos Mulder (1982), Florian &#038; Michael Quistrebert (1976 &#038; 1982), Janis Rafa (1984), belit sağ (1980), Joris Strijbos &#038; Matthijs Munnik (1981 &#038; 1989), Lichun Tseng (1979), David Verbeek (1980)
 Dutch film and video art has undergone significant development in recent years.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead landscape">
<div class="image">
            <a href="https://www.eyefilm.nl/en/exhibition/close-up-%E2%80%93-a-new-generation-of-film-and-video-artists-in-the-netherlands"><br />
	    <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/64ba9_5223_9710cee432d18941ba5d12a701d15817.jpg?b8c429" alt="EYE presents Close-Up – A New Generation of Film and Video Artists in the Netherlands" /><br />
            </a>				</p>
<p class="caption">
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1><em>Close-Up – A New Generation of Film and Video Artists in the Netherlands</em></h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about">January 31–May 22, 2016</p>
<p> <b>EYE Filmmuseum</b> <br/>IJpromenade 1 <br/>1031 KT Amsterdam<br/>The Netherlands </p>
<p> <a href="https://www.eyefilm.nl/en/exhibition/close-up-%E2%80%93-a-new-generation-of-film-and-video-artists-in-the-netherlands">www.eyefilm.nl</a> <br/><a href="https://www.facebook.com/eyefilm/" class="link-social">Facebook</a></p>
</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Fclose-up-a-new-generation-of-film-and-video-artists-in-the-netherlands%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p>From January 31 to May 22, 2016, EYE presents the exhibition <i>Close-Up—A New Generation of Film and Video Artists in the Netherlands</i>. This group exhibition features numerous recent film and video works and spatial installations by a new generation of filmmakers and artists in the Netherlands, who are breaking down the barriers between film, video, and visual art.</p>
<p> Participating artists/ filmmakers:<br/> Melanie Bonajo (1978), Felix Burger (1982), Helen Dowling (1982), Zachary Formwalt (1979), Hamza Halloubi (1982), Mariska de Groot (1982), Cristóbal León &amp; Joaquín Cociña (1980 &amp; 1980), Amos Mulder (1982), Florian &amp; Michael Quistrebert (1976 &amp; 1982), Janis Rafa (1984), belit sağ (1980), Joris Strijbos &amp; Matthijs Munnik (1981 &amp; 1989), Lichun Tseng (1979), David Verbeek (1980)</p>
<p> Dutch film and video art has undergone significant development in recent years. A productive climate has been created in which film-makers and artists with both national and international roots can work and enjoy high-quality education. That has spawned a new generation of prolific makers who demonstrate that the barriers between film, video, and visual art are of little relevance. What unites these individuals is the natural way they incorporate moving image into their work—whether it be video on a single screen, on multiple screens, or as part of a large-scale spatial installation. While artists in previous decades had to battle to use moving images, today it is a medium just like any other tool or technique at their disposal. It is striking that at a time when images have become ubiquitous, many artists feel a need to create images themselves, manipulate existing images, or adopt them for their own ends.</p>
<p> The exhibition offers an impression of the broad spectrum of developments and artistic approaches to the medium of film/video, at a time when there are no longer any dominant movements but, rather, a dynamic and varied range of tendencies. For example, in her performative videos Melanie Bonajo examines the changing relationship of modern man to his surroundings and looks at enigmatic rituals. In his work Zachary Formwalt studies the complex relationship between history, economy, and image production. And in similarly surprising images, Janis Rafa shows catastrophes whose causes remain a mystery. Also on display are films that evoke sensual illusions by powerfully manipulating image and sound (Amos Mulder, Helen Dowling), alongside installations where sound and light constitute key elements (Mariska de Groot).</p>
<p> In the work of belit sağ, video offers the perfect medium for her community engagement. Her poetic meditations establish a direct link between the characteristic features of the medium and her reflections on the current situation in the Islamic world. Hamza Halloubi presents an installation made up of a video, a painting, a photograph and a book. He deploys these elements to tell a non-linear story in which each individual part provokes new interpretations. Also included are artists who study human perception (Strijbos and Munnik), artists who push to the limits the tension between high brow and low brow (Quistrebert brothers), and artists who create a universe all of their own (Felix Burger, Cristóbal León &amp; Joaquín Cociña). Further, the exhibition includes striking installations by makers who are mainly active in cinema. For example, Lichun Tseng pays tribute to 16mm film in what for her is a totally new museum setting, and there is an impressive new installation by filmmaker David Verbeek.</p>
<p> <b>Research Lab</b><br/> Every two weeks EYE invites one of the Dutch art academies to present work by talented students in a special Research Lab, which forms part of the exhibition space. The students organize an opening performance, and the presentation then remains on display for two weeks.</p>
<p> <b>Parallel programme</b><br/> In conjunction with <i>Close-Up</i>, The One Minutes invited artists Felix Burger, Janis Rafa, Helen Dowling, and Melanie Bonajo to each compile a series of one-minute films. The series will premiere at EYE during an entire evening&#8217;s programme put together by the group. Further, EYE is hosting an evening with new Dutch short films, screened in collaboration with the International Film Festival Rotterdam.</p>
</p>
<div><img src="http://editor.e-flux-systems.com/images/5223_281e61944462542e94a00212d33e23b9.jpg?w=150&#038;h=150&#038;c=0" alt="EYE presents Close-Up – A New Generation of Film and Video Artists in the Netherlands"/></div>
</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/close-up-a-new-generation-of-film-and-video-artists-in-the-netherlands/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>FLUIDITY</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/fluidity/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/fluidity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 05:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kunstverein in Hamburg]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005428</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[50 Years Later: The dematerialization of the art object from 1966 to 2016 is a cross-reference show on the permanent state of transformation which surrounds us, focused on the so-called conceptual art that questions the world we live in. A world in which the old forms of work, of behavior, of art no longer fit and new forms have yet to be outlined.
 Sarah Abu Abdallah, Heba Amin, Eleanor Antin, Darren Bader, Tyler Coburn, Simon Denny, Jason Dodge, Maria Eichhorn, Dora García, Liam Gillick, Melanie Gilligan, Goldin+Senneby, Pierre Huyghe, Roberto Jacoby, Hanne Lippard, Lee Lozano, Mathias Poledna, Mladen Stilinović, UBERMORGEN
 The exhibition FLUIDITY surveys the history of "dematerialization," from 1966 to 2016, expanding the scope of this term, beyond past political-conceptual strategies, to include the generation of “digital natives.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead landscape">
<div class="image">
            <a href="http://www.kunstverein.de/"><br />
	    <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/ec616_8307_d36943aa58b36ddc6058210536dc5ce9.jpg?b8c429" alt="FLUIDITY at Kunstverein in Hamburg" /><br />
            </a>				</p>
<p class="caption">Darren Bader, <em>goat as microprocessor that vomits blood to grow basil</em>. Dimensions variable. </p>
</p>
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1><em>FLUIDITY</em></h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about">January 30–April 10, 2016</p>
<p> <b>Kunstverein in Hamburg</b> <br/>Klosterwall 23 <br/>20095 Hamburg<br/>Germany <br/><b>Hours: </b> Tuesday–Sunday 12–6pm </p>
<p> <a href="http://www.kunstverein.de/">www.kunstverein.de</a> <br/><a href="https://www.facebook.com/KunstvereinHamburg/" class="link-social">Facebook</a> / <a href="https://www.twitter.com/kunstvereinhh" class="link-social">Twitter</a></p>
</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Ffluidity%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p>50 Years Later: The dematerialization of the art object from 1966 to 2016 is a cross-reference show on the permanent state of transformation which surrounds us, focused on the so-called conceptual art that questions the world we live in. A world in which the old forms of work, of behavior, of art no longer fit and new forms have yet to be outlined.</p>
<p> <b>Sarah Abu Abdallah, Heba Amin, Eleanor Antin, Darren Bader, Tyler Coburn, Simon Denny, Jason Dodge, Maria Eichhorn, Dora García, Liam Gillick, Melanie Gilligan, Goldin+Senneby, Pierre Huyghe, Roberto Jacoby, Hanne Lippard, Lee Lozano, Mathias Poledna, Mladen Stilinović, UBERMORGEN</b></p>
<p> The exhibition <i>FLUIDITY</i> surveys the history of &#8220;dematerialization,&#8221; from 1966 to 2016, expanding the scope of this term, beyond past political-conceptual strategies, to include the generation of “digital natives.” Society and artistic practices have transformed considerably over the past fifty years. Discussion about these changes—their impact on art, the associated political debates—is precisely what the Kunstverein in Hamburg seeks to ignite.</p>
<p> Conceptual art in the 1960s looked to dissolve the artwork as a material object, in favor of an art formed of ideas and concepts critical of the mechanisms of the market and the modernist canon. In turn, art of the 1990s used participation to reassess economic and institutional structures. Both movements promoted a “dematerialization” of art, intended to actively stimulate the spectator. This term was coined in 1968 by the curator and critic Lucy Lippard; in our highly mediated, digitally-networked world—a world arguably more fluid and dematerialized than ever before—it deserves re-reading. To this end, <i>FLUIDITY </i>juxtaposes art from both periods with conceptual work produced by a young generation of artists, who have developed new strategies and critical appraisals of today’s society.</p>
<p> By tracing “dematerialization” from the 1960s to the present, <i>FLUIDITY</i> reveals broader social tendencies and the ways they have been reflected in political art. These trends include the development of the neoliberal economy and the art market, the increasing “liquification” of both values and currencies, and the dematerialization of processes of work. Through this approach, the exhibition takes aim at the one-sidedness of recent debates on materiality and art. It also enables new discussion and critical reflection: on the contemporary conditions of representation—and the delineation of art as a field.</p>
<p> Curated by Bettina Steinbrügge (Kunstverein in Hamburg), Nina Möntmann (Royal Institute of Art, Stockholm), and Vanessa Joan Müller (Kunsthalle Wien). The exhibition is accompanied by artist talks with Heba Amin, Darren Bader, Tyler Coburn, Simon Denny, Jason Dodge, Hanne Lippard, and a book presentation by Goldin+Senneby. A reader will be published in association with the exhibition.</p>
<p> With friendly support of the Ministry of Culture of the Free and Hanseatic City of Hamburg.</p>
<p> Press contact: <a href="mailto:presse@kunstverein.de">presse@kunstverein.de</a> / T +49 40 322158</p>
</p>
<p><a href="http://www.kunstverein.de/" target="_blank"></a></p>
</p>
<div><a href="http://www.kunstverein.de/"><img src="http://editor.e-flux-systems.com/images/8307_41e838d6585c18ae8f63257c67bda907.jpg?w=150&#038;h=150&#038;c=0" alt="FLUIDITY at Kunstverein in Hamburg"/></a></div>
</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/fluidity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heman Chong</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/heman-chong/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/heman-chong/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 05:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rockbund Art Museum]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005386</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a short story about a gossip column called "Papaya Daily." For ten years, the journalist penned the column for a newspaper. Over time, his daily column became a popular novelty for readers of the newspaper. But little did they know that the stories he wrote were a mix of fact and fiction and that most of them were based on blatant lies. Readers were addicted; they needed small but spectacular escapes from their daily lives.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead landscape">
<div class="image"><a href="http://www.rockbundartmuseum.org"><br /> <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/7295f_9355_669e93925cbc74f035ac17edc44bc718.jpg?b8c429" alt="Heman Chong at Rockbund Art Museum" /><br /> </a></p>
<p class="caption">Heman Chong, <em>The Mysterious Island</em>, 2016. Wood, plastic, iron wire, silk fabric, paint. Courtesy of Rockbund Art Museum.</p>
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1>Heman Chong<br /><i>Ifs, Ands, or Buts</i></h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about">January 23–May 3, 2016</p>
<p><b>Rockbund Art Museum</b> <br />No.20 Huqiu Road <br /> Shanghai<br />China</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rockbundartmuseum.org">www.rockbundartmuseum.org</a> </p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Fheman-chong%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p>This is a short story about a gossip column called &#8220;Papaya Daily.&#8221; For ten years, the journalist penned the column for a newspaper. Over time, his daily column became a popular novelty for readers of the newspaper. But little did they know that the stories he wrote were a mix of fact and fiction and that most of them were based on blatant lies. Readers were addicted; they needed small but spectacular escapes from their daily lives. His editor was a lazy old man who refused to fact-check anything the writers brought in. Therefore, he was free to make up most of his stories based on small bits and pieces he would gather from old magazines and newspapers, updating the stories with slight changes and small twists. For ten years, he wrote whatever he wanted. </p>
<p>Days before his death, the writer gave specific instructions to a very close friend of his about how he would like his last novel to be published. The five parts within the novel would each be published as different books, at a rate of one a year. He had a clear idea of the order of the parts to be published. These instructions were later overturned by his literary executor, without a clear reason. Nobody will ever know the entire truth of the matter. Just think of the six blind men and the elephant. </p>
<p>One of the most innovative and highly successful fundraising programs of a public zoo exists at the Bronx Zoo in the USA. Since 2011, every year during the lead up to Valentine&#8217;s Day, you can name a cockroach at the Bronx Zoo in New York after one of your ex-lovers for a mere 10 USD. </p>
<p>This is a conversation that happened between an American US senator and a general from the Philippines about the official seal of the United Nations. We all know what it looks like. It has a world map with a radar-like grid cast over it, flanked by two Greek laurels. Apparently, the Filipino general had the chance to look at it before it was finalized and threw a fit, screaming &#8220;where is the Philippines on the map?&#8221; The US Senator who was tasked with the design meekly replied, &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry. It&#8217;s too small to be included. If we put in the Philippines it would be no more than a dot,&#8221; to which the Filipino general shouted back, even louder, &#8220;I want that dot!&#8221; Today, if you look closely at the UN seal, you will find a tiny dot between the Pacific Ocean and the South China Sea. </p>
<p>From today onwards, all references to time travel will be banned on official media, including all films and television programs. This is a reaction to a situation where many young girls are attempting to travel back in time to find the love of their lives, a historical character who only exists in a television drama. In the drama series, a girl accidentally time-travels when she jumps off a building, falling into a wormhole. She wakes up and finds herself in the 16th century and was later embroiled in a heated romance with the lead character. Since then, there have been at least 300 time travel attempts by girls in the country, with numerous fatalities.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div><a href="http://www.rockbundartmuseum.org"><img src="http://editor.e-flux-systems.com/images/9355_a06eba686096393e72fd900746d0629e.jpg?w=150&amp;h=150&amp;c=0" alt="Heman Chong at Rockbund Art Museum" /></a></div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/heman-chong/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ARTEFACT festival 2016</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/artefact-festival-2016/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/artefact-festival-2016/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 05:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[STUK Art Centre]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005390</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ For Artefact 2016: Up in the Air, we turn our gaze up towards the skies.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead landscape">
<div class="image"><a href="http://www.artefact-festival.be/en"><br /> <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/f6b31_5028_7fe525d58a6fc634b0cddac867708038.jpg?b8c429" alt="ARTEFACT festival 2016 in STUK Leuven" /><br /> </a></p>
<p class="caption">Berndnaut Smilde, <em>Nimbus D&#8217;Aspremont</em>, 2012. Digital c-type print. Courtesy the artist and Ronchini Gallery.</p>
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1>ARTEFACT festival<br /><i>Up in the Air</i></h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about">February 9–21, 2016</p>
<p><b>STUK Art Centre</b> <br />Naamsestraat 96 <br />3000 Leuven<br />Belgium</p>
<p><a href="http://www.artefact-festival.be/en">www.artefact-festival.be</a> <br /><a class="link-social" href="https://www.facebook.com/STUKLeuven/">Facebook</a> / <a class="link-social" href="https://www.twitter.com/stukleuven">Twitter</a> / <a class="link-social" href="http://www.instagram.com/stukleuven/">Instagram</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Fartefact-festival-2016%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p>&#8220;We come out into the air, reaching for it and bring it inside. In a way, we become air-born(e) as soon as we leave the womb.&#8221;<br /> –Peter Adey, <i>Air: Nature and Culture</i>, p. 45</p>
<p>&#8220;&#8230;our idea of the sky must be reconciled with what we do in it. Our actions there mapped and charted. The sky itself must be woven into the fabric of our societal sense of place.&#8221;<br /> –Megan Prelinger, &#8220;Charting the Sky: On <i>The Atmosphere Guide </i>by Amy Balkin&#8221;</p>
<p>For Artefact 2016: <i>Up in the Air</i>, we turn our gaze up towards the skies. What does our sky consist of and which meanings does it bare? Which systems operate within and what are the legal frameworks that regulate this? How do we deal with this in a local/global context?</p>
<p>Artefact 2016 aims to investigate the poetic, political and economic parameters that guide our relation to airspace. The spiritual dimensions that seem to be closely related to an &#8220;up there,&#8221; the hopes and dreams for which we turn our gaze up, the attempts to understand the intangible and sometimes invisible stand in stark contrast to the more practical, political and economic approaches that organize and regulate our use of air space in areas such as transportation, scanning and surveillance and air quality control.</p>
<p>Commercial development of unmanned aerial vehicles (drones) and the lack of a functioning legal framework in relation to it has turned the topic of how to run airspace into a burning issue. President Barack Obama himself exemplified the not-in-my-backyard attitude beautifully when an UAV landed, well, in his backyard.</p>
<p><i>Up in the Air</i> wishes to place these contemporary societal questions in a broader investigative context that brings forth our relation to airspace regardless of the technologies at hand.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Participating artists </b></p>
<p><b>Expo</b><br /> James Turrell (United States), Paolo Di Trapani &amp; CoeLux (Italy), Ief Spincemaille (Belgium), Frederic Geurts (Belgium), Rob Sweere (Netherlands), Berndnaut Smilde (Netherlands), Alistair McClymont (United Kingdom), Charlotte Charbonnel (France), Vincent &amp; Lawrence Malstaf (Belgium – Belgium/Norway), Bilal Bahir (Iraq/Belgium), Sjoerd Knibbeler (Netherlands), Javier Pérez (Spain), Marije Baalman (Netherlands), Amy Balkin (United States), James Bridle (United Kingdom), The Center for Genomic Gastronomy (United States/Norway/Ireland) &amp; Nicola Twilley (United States/United Kingdom) Alicia Framis (Spain), Laurent Grasso (France), Ruben Pater (Netherlands), Forensic Architecture (United Kingdom), Superflux (United Kingdom/India), Wesley Goatley &amp; Georgina Voss (United Kingdom), Bigert &amp; Bergström (Sweden) and Liam Young (Australia)</p>
<p><b>Artefact Music Festival</b><br /> Lorenzo Senni (Italy), Hiele (Belgium), Hantrax (Belgium), Powell (United Kingdom), Fis (New Zealand), Sagat (Belgium), Kassett (Belgium), FilosofischeStilte (Netherlands), Nosedrip (Belgium), Samuel Kerridge (United Kingdom), Shapednoise (Italy), Kiss The Anus Of A Black Cat (Belgium), William Basinski (United States), Amatorski (Belgium), John Bence (United Kingdom), Ansatz Der Maschine (Belgium), Christina Vantzou (United States), Rafael Anton Irisarri (United States), Peter Kirn (Canada), Darsha Hewitt (Canada)</p>
<p><b>Performances and lectures</b><br /> Rodrigro Sobarzo (Chile/Netherlands), Vlad Ionescu (Belgium), Daniel Blanga-Gubbay (Italy), Bart Remes (Netherlands), Stijn Postema (Netherlands)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>Expo guide / publication</b> to download from <a href="http://www.artefact-festival.be/en">www.artefact-festival.be</a> from February 9, 2016</p>
<div> </div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/artefact-festival-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Open call for artists: Swedish memorial to the victims of the tsunami in Southeast Asia in 2004</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/open-call-for-artists-swedish-memorial-to-the-victims-of-the-tsunami-in-southeast-asia-in-2004/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/open-call-for-artists-swedish-memorial-to-the-victims-of-the-tsunami-in-southeast-asia-in-2004/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 05:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Public Art Agency Sweden]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005388</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Preliminary budget for the realisation of the memorial: EUR 400,000
 On December 26, 2004, Southeast Asia suffered one of the greatest natural disasters in history, killing a quarter of a million people. With 543 dead and some 1,500 wounded among the victims, this was a great tragedy to Sweden. 
 In conjunction with the 10th anniversary of the disaster, the Swedish government has decided to create a memorial site in Sweden to honour the memory of those who lost their lives, and to create a place where their relatives and friends can gather.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead landscape">
<div class="image"><a href="http://www.statenskonstrad.se/en/"><br /> <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/7b238_7901_e4fbb36b8ceeed9cb475ff0605f995b1.jpg?b8c429" alt="Open call for artists: Swedish memorial to the victims of the tsunami in Southeast Asia in 2004" /><br /> </a></p>
<p class="caption">Photo: Melker Dahlstrand.</p>
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1>Open call for artists: Swedish memorial to the victims of the tsunami in Southeast Asia in 2004</h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about"><b>Application deadline:</b> March 10, 2016</p>
<p><a href="http://www.statenskonstrad.se/en/">www.statenskonstrad.se</a> </p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Fopen-call-for-artists-swedish-memorial-to-the-victims-of-the-tsunami-in-southeast-asia-in-2004%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p>Preliminary budget for the realisation of the memorial: EUR 400,000</p>
<p>On December 26, 2004, Southeast Asia suffered one of the greatest natural disasters in history, killing a quarter of a million people. With 543 dead and some 1,500 wounded among the victims, this was a great tragedy to Sweden. </p>
<p>In conjunction with the 10th anniversary of the disaster, the Swedish government has decided to create a memorial site in Sweden to honour the memory of those who lost their lives, and to create a place where their relatives and friends can gather. </p>
<p>The memorial will be located on the southern side of Djurgården, in a beautiful parkland area close to central Stockholm. Rather than a monument, the competition is aimed to generate proposals for a designed space for contemplation, memory and celebration of the people who died. The artwork shall provide a setting that surrounds visitors in close dialogue with the landscape. </p>
<p>The memory of a catastrophe holds a complexity of emotions, ranging from grief to light-hearted remembrances of our loved ones. The artistic design should allow for this wide range of emotions, with openness and the potential for personal interpretations. </p>
<p>Reflecting the shared loss caused by the catastrophe, the memorial will also honour bonds across national borders. </p>
<p>The competition is organised by the Public Art Agency Sweden and the National Property Board Sweden. The first step is a call for entries, where five competitors will be chosen. Entries are accepted from individual artists, artist groups or artists collaborating with landscape architects. Entries must be submitted no later than March 10, 2016.</p>
<p>Background information for entries can be downloaded from: <a href="http://www.statenskonstrad.se/en/">statenskonstrad.se/en</a></p>
<div><img src="http://editor.e-flux-systems.com/images/7901_47918b70e01509d33952b809dd6fb3f3.jpg?w=550" alt="Open call for artists: Swedish memorial to the victims of the tsunami in Southeast Asia in 2004" /></div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/open-call-for-artists-swedish-memorial-to-the-victims-of-the-tsunami-in-southeast-asia-in-2004/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Francesco Vezzoli</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/francesco-vezzoli-2/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/francesco-vezzoli-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 05:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[MUSEION of Modern and Contemporary Art Bolzano]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005392</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ Museion's 2016 programme opens with an exceptional double exhibition. Francesco Vezzoli is curating an exhibition of the Museion collection as guest curator, and presenting, as an artist, the first retrospective of his sculptural work. Entitled Museo Museion, the double show is set to take over the whole of the Bolzano venue.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead portrait">
<div class="image"><a href="http://www.museion.it/?lang=en"><br /> <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/a6c37_jan29_bolzano_img.jpg?b8c429" alt="Francesco Vezzoli at Museion" /><br /> </a></p>
<p class="caption">Francesco Vezzoli, <i>Antique not Antique: Self-portrait as a Crying Roman Togatus</i>, 2012. Courtesy of the artist.</p>
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1>Francesco Vezzoli<br /><i>Museo Museion</i></h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about"><b>Opening:</b> January 29, 2016, 7pm</p>
<p><b>MUSEION of modern and contemporary art Bolzano<br /></b>Piazza Piero Siena 1<br />39100 Bolzano<br />Italy</p>
<p><a href="http://www.museion.it/?lang=en">www.museion.it</a><br /><a href="https://twitter.com/MuseionBZ">Twitter</a> / <a href="https://www.facebook.com/museion.bozen/">Facebook</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Ffrancesco-vezzoli-2%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p><b>Sculpture exhibition <br />curated by Letizia Ragaglia</b> <br />January 30–May 16, 2016</p>
<p><b>Exhibition of the Museion collection <br />curated by Francesco Vezzoli</b> <br />January 30–November 6, 2016</p>
<p>Museion&#8217;s 2016 programme opens with an <b>exceptional double exhibition</b>. Francesco Vezzoli is curating an exhibition of the Museion collection as guest curator, and presenting, as an artist, the first retrospective of his sculptural work. Entitled <i>Museo Museion</i>, the double show is set to take over the whole of the Bolzano venue. It opens with an imposing wallpaper based on a painting by Giovanni Paolo Pannini, which immerses the ground floor of Museion in the atmosphere of an eighteenth-century picture gallery. </p>
<p>From embroidering masterpieces of abstract art to the more recent historical polychrome sculptures of <i>Teatro Romano</i> (MoMA PS1, New York 2015), Vezzoli has always forged a <b>meaningful yet irreverent dialogue with the past</b>—be it ancient history, or the history of film, images, or power. An anarchist at heart, Vezzoli skillfully subverts entrenched value systems by using rhetorical devices such as <b>antithesis </b>and<b> hyperbole</b>, and sparking <b>semantic and temporal shifts</b>. This modus operandi is evident in the shows for the Bolzano museum. </p>
<p>Francesco Vezzoli&#8217;s exhibition reinterprets part of the <b>Museion collection</b> by making it interface with <b>masterpieces from Western art history</b> kept in major European and American museums. <br /> Frames from famous paintings by Michelangelo, Raphael, Caravaggio, Ingres and many more, appear in trompe l&#8217;œil style, around works from the Museion collection. When selecting the pieces, Vezzoli paid special attention to <b>minor works</b> from the museum&#8217;s collection that are not frequently exhibited. The show, which presents 30 works, including paintings, photography and installations, is presented as a journey through different genres—portrait, self-portrait, still life, landscape, etc. In each section there are also <b>pieces by Vezzoli himself</b>, while the Study Collection venue hosts a special section devoted to <b>graphic works.</b> </p>
<p>The interplay of associations and deconstructions between different eras and styles is also evident in the sculpture exhibition. In the spacious areas on the fourth floor, an imposing platform displays ancient works that interface with new pieces by the artist. Vezzoli&#8217;s <b>incisive, ironic touch</b> brings us <b>playful</b> <b>critical</b> <b>reworkings</b> of the <b>classical</b> Roman portrait <b>tradition</b>, as can be seen in the self-portrait statue <i>Antique not Antique: Self-portrait as a Crying Roman Togatus </i>(2012) or his interpretation of ancient mythology, as in the group <i>Metamorfosi (Self-Portrait as Apollo killing the Satyr Marsyas)</i> (2015).<i> </i>Interventions that are bold and provocative, but also based on solid <b>scientific foundations</b>. This is the case with the marble busts in the series <b>&#8220;True Colors&#8221;</b> dating to soon after Christ, to which Vezzoli restored the colour, based on archaeological evidence and incontrovertible scientific studies. The artist directs his creativity not only to ancient art, but also <b>modern masterpieces and contemporary icons</b>, such as the actress <b>Sophia Loren</b>, transformed into one of <b>de Chirico&#8217;s muses.</b> The sculpture exhibition also features a <b>new work</b> created for the occasion, <i>BI (A Roman Marble Janiform Herm Head, circa 2nd Century A.D.)</i>, 2015.</p>
<p>In the words of Anna Coliva, director of the Galleria Borghese in Rome, in her contribution to the exhibition catalogue, &#8220;Choosing to focus on sculpture in this show promises to produce one of the most intense exhibition experiences that Vezzoli could opt for at this stage in his career.&#8221; </p>
<p>&#8220;For Francesco Vezzoli it is not a question of choosing between a classic or eccentric mode of narrating the history of art, but rather opening up to multiple worlds and multiple histories of art, pursuing an ongoing conversation. For visitors to the exhibition, <i>Museo Museion</i> will be like experiencing one huge installation,&#8221; comments Letizia Ragaglia, Museion&#8217;s Director.</p>
<p> The exhibition will be accompanied by a catalogue in three languages (Italian/German/English) published by Mousse Publishing with texts by Anna Coliva, Cerith Wyn Evans, Letizia Ragaglia, Dieter Roelstraete and a conversation between Francesco Vezzoli and Cristiana Perrella. </p>
<p>To consult the programme of related events, click <a href="http://www.museion.it/events-2/collateral-events/?lang=en">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Institutional partners:</strong><br />Provincia Autonoma di Bolzano / Autonome Provinz Bozen<br />Fondazione Cassa de Risparmio di Bolzano / Stiftung Südtiroler Sparkasse</p>
<p><strong>Sponsor of the exhibition catalogue:</strong><br />hmc – heart mind creativity, Bolzano</p>
<p><b>Member of AMACI, Associazione Musei d&#8217;Arte contemporanea italiani</b></p>
<div> </div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/francesco-vezzoli-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yan Xing: Performance of a Massacre</title>
		<link>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/yan-xing-performance-of-a-massacre/</link>
		<comments>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/yan-xing-performance-of-a-massacre/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 05:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stedelijk Museum Amsterdam]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.e-flux.com/?p=9005394</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Stedelijk Museum Amsterdam presents a new performance by Beijing- and Los Angeles-based artist Yan Xing. In Performance of a Massacre the artist addresses the problematics of remembrance and representation through the re-staging of current and past dramatic events.
  
 Yan Xing directly—yet carefully—reflects on historical tragedies by confusing the viewpoints of both victims and perpetrators. By interlacing the performance with extracts of authentic reports of recent events, the artist disrupts the representation of the present and the past.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="pageHead portrait">
<div class="image"><a href="http://www.stedelijk.nl/en"><br /> <img src="http://www.e-flux.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/89498_8859_0f73516a3bd93161645293bd76056c5f.gif?b8c429" alt="Stedelijk Museum Amsterdam presents Yan Xing: Performance of a Massacre" /><br /> </a></p>
<p class="caption"> </p>
</div>
<div class="headRight">
<h1><em>Yan Xing: Performance of a Massacre</em></h1>
<p class="dates"></p>
<p class="about">January 29, 2016, 8–9pm</p>
<p><a href="http://www.stedelijk.nl/en">www.stedelijk.nl</a> <br /><a class="link-social" href="https://www.facebook.com/Stedelijk">Facebook</a> / <a class="link-social" href="https://www.twitter.com/stedelijk">Twitter</a> / <a class="link-social" href="http://www.instagram.com/stedelijkmuseum/">Instagram</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="share">
	<!-- AddThis Button BEGIN -->
		<div class="socialIcons">
		<div class="addthis_toolbox addthis_default_style">
		     	<a href="http://facebook.com/sharer/sharer.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.e-flux.com%2Fannouncements%2Fyan-xing-performance-of-a-massacre%2F" target="share_fb"><img src="/images/share_fb.png?b8c429" /></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_twitter"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_google_plusone"></a>
			<a class="addthis_button_email"></a>
			<span class="shareText">Share</span>
		</div>
		</div>
		<!-- AddThis Button END -->
</div>
<div class="columns">
<div class="col1">
<p>The Stedelijk Museum Amsterdam presents a new performance by Beijing- and Los Angeles-based artist Yan Xing. In <a href="http://www.stedelijk.nl/en/calendar/performances/yan-xing-performance-of-a-massacre"><i>Performance of a Massacre</i></a> the artist addresses the problematics of remembrance and representation through the re-staging of current and past dramatic events.<br />  <br /> Yan Xing directly—yet carefully—reflects on historical tragedies by confusing the viewpoints of both victims and perpetrators. By interlacing the performance with extracts of authentic reports of recent events, the artist disrupts the representation of the present and the past. The performance is enacted by 37 performers, trying to hide in the various galleries throughout the museum. They are a group of high school students who have been undergoing training at a winter camp nearby. Tensely and nervously, they talk to the audience, each from his or her own standpoint, about a massacre. Suddenly, one of the students calls out to the other students for help and the audience will witness a drastic change of scenery.</p>
<p>The performers recite personal stories from tragic events. Perspectives, personas, and locations get interchanged. What begins as faceless narratives, represented by softly spoken words, gradually leads to the representation of an unjustified and inescapable event and a group plea, criticism, doubt, or inquiry for acknowledgement of collective responsibility. By questioning our moral considerations for reporting historical tragedies, Yan Xing critically examines what it means to have a cultural memory, how memory gets mediated through the manipulation and organization of language, and the (re-)presentation of public events. Although the work is politically ambiguous, he says, the work he is trying to achieve has or should have no political slant and shows the powerlessness of the audience when it comes to the mediation of memory.</p>
<p><b>Yan Xing</b> (1986, Chongqing, China) lives and works in Beijing and Los Angeles. Yan Xing&#8217;s work combines diverse media such as performance, video, photography, and installation. His works circulate around large themes such as negativity, resistance, and order, as well as exploring their complex interrelations.</p>
<p>In 2012 Yan Xing won the Best Young Artist Award from CCAA (Chinese Contemporary Art Award) and also received a nomination for the Future Generation Art Prize from the Victor Pinchuk Foundation. Yan Xing has exhibited and performed extensively; recent major exhibitions include 3rd Ural Industrial Biennial of Contemporary Art, Yekaterinburg, Russia (2015); <i>28 Chinese</i>, Rubell Family Collection, Miami (2013); and <i>ON | OFF: China&#8217;s Young Artists in Concept and Practice</i>, Ullens Center for Contemporary Art (UCCA), Beijing (2013).</p>
<div> </div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.e-flux.com/announcements/yan-xing-performance-of-a-massacre/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using xcache

 Served from: www.e-flux.com @ 2016-01-30 16:07:23 by W3 Total Cache -->